<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on StaPH-B</title>
    <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on StaPH-B</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.staphb.org/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>StaPH-B Videos</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</guid>
      <description>Every month the StaPH-B community gets together for an online presentation. These presenations are recorded and presented here for your review.
August 2020 - Candida Auris NGS StaPH-B&amp;rsquo;s August call featured Nancy Chow and Rory Welsh of the CDC mycotic diseases branch. Nancy and Rory spoke about the growing threat of the drug resistant organism Candida auris, and some initiatives that are underway to detect and prevent the spread of this particular pathogen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 Public Health Resources</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/sars-cov-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 15:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/sars-cov-2/</guid>
      <description>This page will server as a starting point for public health laboratories searchgin for information on SARS-CoV-2 sequencing, bioinformatics, and genomic epidemiology. A full page version of these resources can be found HERE.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextfow and AWS Batch Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/nextflow_aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/nextflow_aws/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Services Batch is a service that allows users to submit jobs to job queues while specifying the application to be run and compute resources that are needed by the job. Working in concert with Nextflow, AWS Batch can be configured to run Nextflow processes in defined compute environments minimizing the cost of cloud resources.
Useful Resources This tutorial was written using Alex Peltzer&amp;rsquo;s guide and Anthony Underwood&amp;rsquo;s guide as resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 21:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Connecting to Cloud Resources Many people already know how to connect to their VMs through putty of MobaXterm, but the Google Chrome Browser provides a very nice service called &amp;ldquo;Chrome Remote Desktop&amp;rdquo; which allows for a fast and secure GUI connection to your VMs. Here is a short video showing you how to set up Chrome Remote Desktop on your VM.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Repositories of Public Health Interest</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/software_repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 23:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/software_repos/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Pages  StaPH-B Github Repositories - home directory for many StaPH-B repositories including Docker Builds, StaPH-B Toolkit, CDPHE scripts, and the Utah Reference Free scripts. NCBI AMRFinderPlus - GitHub repository of the NCBI Antimicrobial Resistance Gene Finder (AMRFinderPlus). This is the package used by the NCBI Pathogen Detection Browswer to genotype isolates with respece to antimicrobial resistance.  DockerHub  StaPH-B DockerHub - DockerHub site for all the StaPH-B containers created by StaPH-B members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Resources for Molecular and Genomic Epidemiology</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</guid>
      <description>The public health bioinformatics community is continuosly producing new training content for laboratorians and epidemiologists. Much of this focuses on new technology and its applications. But there is already a wealth of information and training content available if one knows where to look. This section hopes to serve as a resource where currently available material is identified and links provided to that content.
New York Integrated Food Safety Center of Excellence The NY Integrated Food Safety CoE has extensive online materials for molecular epidemiology targeting both the laboratorian and epidemiologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aws_test - UNDER DEVELOPMENT</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/aws_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/aws_test/</guid>
      <description>If you would like to comment on the document below please click here.
An easier reading html version of this document can be found here.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary of Bioinformatic Terms</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</guid>
      <description>This glossary is adapted from Kelsey Florek and her Midwest Region AMD Pages on GitHub. The glossary is reproduced here for the benefit of those who cannot access GitHub.
Bioinformatics This discipline is involved in the collection, analysis, and storage of complex biological data, including, but not limited to genetic data. The field combines computer science, statistics, and several aspects of biology to be able to understand highly complex data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
