<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on StaPH-B</title>
    <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on StaPH-B</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:17:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.staphb.org/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Resources for Molecular and Genomic Epidemiology</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</guid>
      <description>The public health bioinformatics community is continuosly producing new training content for laboratorians and epidemiologists. Much of this focuses on new technology and its applications. But there is already a wealth of information and training content available if one knows where to look. This section hopes to serve as a resource where currently available material is identified and links provided to that content.
New York Integrated Food Safety Center of Excellence The NY Integrated Food Safety CoE has extensive online materials for molecular epidemiology targeting both the laboratorian and epidemiologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary of Bioinformatic Terms</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</guid>
      <description>This glossary is adapted from Kelsey Florek and her Midwest Region AMD Pages on GitHub. The glossary is reproduced here for the benefit of those who cannot access GitHub.
Bioinformatics This discipline is involved in the collection, analysis, and storage of complex biological data, including, but not limited to genetic data. The field combines computer science, statistics, and several aspects of biology to be able to understand highly complex data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StaPH-B Videos</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 20:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</guid>
      <description>Every month the StaPH-B community gets together for an online presentation. These presenations are recoreded and presented here for your review.
StaPH-B Monthly Call - December 2019 For our December 2019 call, we have invited Lucy Li and David Dynerman from the Chan-Zuckerberg BioHub to speak about Madrone, a user-friendly bioinformatics platform for cluster analysis and AMR gene detection for carbapenem-resistant Enterobacteriaceae isolates. Madrone was developed in collaboration between the Chan-Zuckerberg BioHub and the Alameda County (CA) Public Health Laboratory to address Alameda&#39;s bioinformatics needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>