<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StaPH-B</title>
    <link>http://www.staphb.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on StaPH-B</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:06:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.staphb.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>StaPH-B Videos</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/staphb-videos/</guid>
      <description>Every month the StaPH-B community gets together for an online presentation. These presenations are recorded and presented here for your review.
April 2020 - COVID-19 Special Episode 3: Local Nextstrain As a follow up to our last call, during which Alli Black from the Bedford laboratory spoke about the NextStrain platform and its applications in COVID-19 response efforts, we invited Heather Blankenship&amp;ndash;a bioinformatics scientist at the Michigan public health laboratory&amp;ndash;to speak about her experience setting up a local NextStrain build for real-time COVID-19 surveillance in Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextfow and AWS Batch Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/nextflow_aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/nextflow_aws/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Services Batch is a service that allows users to submit jobs to job queues while specifying the application to be run and compute resources that are needed by the job. Working in concert with Nextflow, AWS Batch can be configured to run Nextflow processes in defined compute environments minimizing the cost of cloud resources.
Useful Resources This tutorial was written using Alex Peltzer&amp;rsquo;s guide and Anthony Underwood&amp;rsquo;s guide as resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCBI and Data Sharing - UNDER DEVELOPMENT</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/training/ncbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 16:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/training/ncbi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 21:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Connecting to Cloud Resources Many people already know how to connect to their VMs through putty of MobaXterm, but the Google Chrome Browser provides a very nice service called &amp;ldquo;Chrome Remote Desktop&amp;rdquo; which allows for a fast and secure GUI connection to your VMs. Here is a short video showing you how to set up Chrome Remote Desktop on your VM.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack Training for Scientific Communication</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/training/slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 19:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/training/slack/</guid>
      <description>MTN Region Slack Training In March, Kelly Oakeson gave a webinar on how to use Slack for effective communication, especially within a regional scientific community. The video for this webinar is shared below for those who could not attend.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMR Detection Using NGS</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/training/amr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/training/amr/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying Webinar Series | February 2020 | AMR Detection Using NGS For our February 2020 webinar, we discuss how bacterial species identification is conducted using NGS data. This webinar will examine the different algorithms and databases used for AMR detection, with an emphasis on CGE’s ResFinder and NCBI’s AMRFinderPlus. Upon completion of the webinar, attendees will 1) understand the algorithms behind AMR detection using NGS, 2) the difference between gene based and mutational resistance, and 3) the advantages and limitations of these methods compared to traditional phenotypic testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbial Species ID Using ANI and Mash</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/training/bacterial-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/training/bacterial-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;demystifying-webinar-series--january-2020--microbial-species-identification&#34;&gt;Demystifying Webinar Series | January 2020 | Microbial Species Identification&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our January 2020 webinar, we discuss how bacterial species identification is conducted using NGS data. Topics focus on both average nucleotide identify (ANI) and Mash, how they are similar, how they are different, and when it is appropriate to use one versus the other.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2Tk6nTUaz40&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://storage.googleapis.com/staphb-resources/staphb-org-files/training-webinar-slides/Microbial_ID_webinary_January_2020_MTN_Region.pdf&#34;&gt;Click here for slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Repositories of Public Health Interest</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/software_repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 23:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/software_repos/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Pages  StaPH-B Github Repositories - home directory for many StaPH-B repositories including Docker Builds, StaPH-B Toolkit, CDPHE scripts, and the Utah Reference Free scripts. NCBI AMRFinderPlus - GitHub repository of the NCBI Antimicrobial Resistance Gene Finder (AMRFinderPlus). This is the package used by the NCBI Pathogen Detection Browswer to genotype isolates with respece to antimicrobial resistance.  DockerHub  StaPH-B DockerHub - DockerHub site for all the StaPH-B containers created by StaPH-B members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Resources for Molecular and Genomic Epidemiology</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/online-resources/</guid>
      <description>The public health bioinformatics community is continuosly producing new training content for laboratorians and epidemiologists. Much of this focuses on new technology and its applications. But there is already a wealth of information and training content available if one knows where to look. This section hopes to serve as a resource where currently available material is identified and links provided to that content.
New York Integrated Food Safety Center of Excellence The NY Integrated Food Safety CoE has extensive online materials for molecular epidemiology targeting both the laboratorian and epidemiologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary of Bioinformatic Terms</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/resources/glossary/</guid>
      <description>This glossary is adapted from Kelsey Florek and her Midwest Region AMD Pages on GitHub. The glossary is reproduced here for the benefit of those who cannot access GitHub.
Bioinformatics This discipline is involved in the collection, analysis, and storage of complex biological data, including, but not limited to genetic data. The field combines computer science, statistics, and several aspects of biology to be able to understand highly complex data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/history/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning&amp;hellip; Who are we? How did this all begin? Well, at first there were four: Kevin Libuit, Sean Wang, Kelly Oakeson, and Joel Sevinsky. And by four we mean there were at least four of us bothering Heather Carleton for help with bioinformatics of enteric pathogens around winter 2016/2017. Heather suggested, probably to save herself from answering too many questions and often the same question four times, that the group of should &amp;ldquo;talk amongst ourselves&amp;rdquo;, and our contact information was shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the StaPH-B website!</title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>It has been a long time coming, but we have decided to support a website where we can aggregate all the training and information in genomic epidemiology in one location, as well as provide new and inique content for public health bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.staphb.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.staphb.org/about/</guid>
      <description>About StaPH-B The State Public Health Bioinformatics Group (StaPH-B) is a consortium of public health scientists interested in addressing the common barriers impeding bioinformatics implementation in state public health laboratories. Our efforts are focused in the following areas:
 Building and sustaining an appropriate bioinformatics infrastructure within regional state PHLs Training public health scientists on the fundamentals of bioinformatics Development of bioinformatics applications, tools and pipelines Facilitation of CLIA approval for Bioinformatics applications, tools and pipelines Partner with the CDC and APHL to ensure compatibility and utility of our efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>